ARAVINDH PRASANNA

aravindhprasanna26@gmail.com 9787097258 No.3/1, Arunachalam Street E.B Colony Kalinjur ,Vellore-632006

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Zealous, ethical, goal driven graduate engineer and a student of science with a deep desire to set an example in the work that I do by applying my skill set.

EDUCATION

Bachelor in Mechanical Engineering from

SRM Easwari Engineering College in year 2017 with 64.6%

Higher Secondary Examnation from Sunbeam Matriculation Higher Secondary School in year 2013 with 82.67%

Secondary Examination from ST.Marks Matriculation Higher Secondary School in year 2011 with 74.6%

TECHNICAL SKILLS

CAD Tools: CREO - 5

Certification Course from AKSANS

(Nov - Feb 2019, PTC Authorized Training Center)

CATIA - V5R20

Certification Course from AKSANS

(Mar - May 2020, PTC Authorized Training Center)

2D & 3D, Drawing Confirming GD&T.

EXPERIENCE SUMMARY

Sept 2021-Nov 2021 HINDUJA TECH PVTLTD

Power Train Design Engineer.

H6 2V BSVI engine assembly drawing consists of more than one component. This assembly drawing represents how the components fit together by Generating 3D views of assembled components by which addition of exploded views in details.

Assembly drawings helps to communicate line Executives how to assemble every part of engine and also giving details like tightening torque, tightening sequence, etc.

July 2019 – Sep 2021 Mahindra & Mahindra Ltd, (Mahindra Research Valley, Chennai)

Vehicle Validation

Vehicle Preparation for the validation trials, Before and after preparation for running PDI (Pre delivery Inspection) Engines.

Jan 2018 to Jul 2018 Delphi TVS Diesel Systems Ltd., Chennai

Production Line

Worked in various (Perkins & JCB) Pump Assembly & Testing in Production Department. Investigation pump performance for delivery pressure and leaking. Inspected various parts for its defects.

In Drive Shaft Assembly, Inspected various parts for its defects such as Y, Z, AA, AL component drive shaft using dial gauge.

Application: Components which are used in FIP for the Application of JCB, Tractor Engines.

DECLARATION

I hereby declare that the above all information are to my best knowledge.